<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Agriculture on Robin Choudhury</title>
    <link>https://robchoudhury.com/tags/agriculture/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Agriculture on Robin Choudhury</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2019 Robin Choudhury</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://robchoudhury.com/tags/agriculture/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Sketchnotes of Ying-Yu Liao&#39;s tomato spot talk</title>
      <link>https://robchoudhury.com/art/liao-tomato/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robchoudhury.com/art/liao-tomato/</guid>
      <description>Ying-Yu Liao gave a nice seminar about her ongoing PhD work looking at Magnesium Oxide nanoparticles and their use for control of bacterial tomato spot disease.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aloe painting for birthday card</title>
      <link>https://robchoudhury.com/art/aloe-painting/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robchoudhury.com/art/aloe-painting/</guid>
      <description>I have three awesome sisters, so this was the painting I made for my sister Mimi&amp;rsquo;s birthday card. I&amp;rsquo;m lucky that my work is close by to some really cool gardens on campus, including the Ficke Garden just north of the Microbiology Building.
I put this art up on my redbubble account (https://www.redbubble.com/people/robchoudhury) so that I could buy it in sticker format</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sketchnotes of Neil McRoberts&#39; HLB talk</title>
      <link>https://robchoudhury.com/art/mcroberts-hlb/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robchoudhury.com/art/mcroberts-hlb/</guid>
      <description>My former advisor Neil McRoberts gave a seminar at the UF Plant Pathology department about his work on managing the citrus HLB outbreak in California. They have currently found about 1000 trees in the LA basin with HLB, and the program spends about $40m each year, which he has to fight tooth and nail to get. The disease could devestate California&amp;rsquo;s citrus market, so managing it early is critical.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azalea painting for birthday card</title>
      <link>https://robchoudhury.com/art/azalea-painting/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robchoudhury.com/art/azalea-painting/</guid>
      <description>I have three awesome sisters, so this was the painting I made for my sister Abby&amp;rsquo;s birthday card. Florida lights up with tons of azaleas every spring, and my house is surrounded by them, so I wanted her to get a glimpse of some while they were in season. I put this art up on my redbubble account (https://www.redbubble.com/people/robchoudhury) so that I could buy it in sticker format</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Climate Change Book Chapter</title>
      <link>https://robchoudhury.com/art/climate-change-painting/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robchoudhury.com/art/climate-change-painting/</guid>
      <description>I was part of an upcoming book chapter on the threat of climate change for pathogens, and all I could think of was the idea of pathogens on the horizon. I painted a watercolor illustration for the book chapter, maybe it&amp;rsquo;ll be used as the book cover! The painting draws inspiration from Outrun/vaporwave sort of art that became popular in the late 2010&amp;rsquo;s, although the color palette is wayyyy off, it should be neon blue and pink!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amanita Birthday Card Painting</title>
      <link>https://robchoudhury.com/art/amanita-bday-painting/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robchoudhury.com/art/amanita-bday-painting/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m lucky to have some great sisters, so I drew an Amanita and painted it with watercolors and a sharpie pen as a birthday card for her!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Haiti Crop Production</title>
      <link>https://robchoudhury.com/post/haiti-production/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robchoudhury.com/post/haiti-production/</guid>
      <description>Full analysis here
Haiti is one of our nation&amp;rsquo;s nearest neighbors, and has been a key player in world history over the past 200 years. The Haitian revolution took nearly 15 years and cost countless lives, but resulted in one of the first nations that was slave-free and ruled by non-whites and former captives. The loss of Haiti (then called Saint-Domingue) forced the cash-starved Napoleon to sell the Louisiana territory to the United States, one of the single largest land purchases in our countries history.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Homestead Avocado Ratings</title>
      <link>https://robchoudhury.com/post/avocado-ratings/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robchoudhury.com/post/avocado-ratings/</guid>
      <description>Full analysis here
Global avocado production mostly focuses in Mexico, with the most prominent variety being &amp;lsquo;Hass&amp;rsquo;. I work on a project researching a disease of avocados (and other plants in the same family, Lauraceae) that causes rapid death, laurel wilt. Avocados in Florida are threatened by laurel wilt. Most production occurs in Miami-Dade county, mostly around the Homestead production region. The avocados grown in Florida tend to be of the West Indian races, whereas Hass are Mexican-Guatamalan hybrid races.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summary measures of predictive power associated with logistic regression models of disease risk</title>
      <link>https://robchoudhury.com/publication/gareth_sdm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robchoudhury.com/publication/gareth_sdm/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Miami Mango Ratings</title>
      <link>https://robchoudhury.com/post/miami-mango-ratings/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robchoudhury.com/post/miami-mango-ratings/</guid>
      <description>Full analysis here
Mangos are grown widely in South Florida, but only a few varieties ever make it north, because they don’t really ship well and there isn’t a huge market. I ended up receiving some rare varieties from a collaborator down south, and I wanted to know how they ranked one to another, so my wife and I rated the different varieties.
The Data My wife and I rated the mangoes over the course of about a week, tasting the different varieties as they felt more and more ripe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Climate change, carbon dioxide, and pest biology, managing the future: coffee as a case study</title>
      <link>https://robchoudhury.com/publication/climate_change_coffee/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robchoudhury.com/publication/climate_change_coffee/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Network analysis: a systems framework to address grand challenges in plant pathology</title>
      <link>https://robchoudhury.com/publication/network_annualreview/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robchoudhury.com/publication/network_annualreview/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A framework for optimizing phytosanitary thresholds in seed systems</title>
      <link>https://robchoudhury.com/publication/phytosanitarythresholds/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robchoudhury.com/publication/phytosanitarythresholds/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Laurel wilt in natural and agricultural ecosystems: understanding the drivers and scales of complex pathosystems</title>
      <link>https://robchoudhury.com/publication/laurel_wilt_review/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robchoudhury.com/publication/laurel_wilt_review/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spatiotemporal patterns in the airborne dispersal of spinach downy mildew</title>
      <link>https://robchoudhury.com/publication/spatiotemporal_sdm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robchoudhury.com/publication/spatiotemporal_sdm/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Season-long dynamics of spinach downy mildew determined by spore trapping and disease incidence</title>
      <link>https://robchoudhury.com/publication/season_long_sdm/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robchoudhury.com/publication/season_long_sdm/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First report of Cytospora punicae causing wood canker and branch dieback of pomegranate (Punica granatum) in the United States</title>
      <link>https://robchoudhury.com/publication/franci_cytospora/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robchoudhury.com/publication/franci_cytospora/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First report of Diplodia seriata causing pear branch canker dieback in California</title>
      <link>https://robchoudhury.com/publication/pear_diplodia/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robchoudhury.com/publication/pear_diplodia/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>