<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Art on Robin Choudhury</title>
    <link>https://robchoudhury.com/tags/art/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Art on Robin Choudhury</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2019 Robin Choudhury</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://robchoudhury.com/tags/art/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Sketchnotes of Ying-Yu Liao&#39;s tomato spot talk</title>
      <link>https://robchoudhury.com/art/liao-tomato/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robchoudhury.com/art/liao-tomato/</guid>
      <description>Ying-Yu Liao gave a nice seminar about her ongoing PhD work looking at Magnesium Oxide nanoparticles and their use for control of bacterial tomato spot disease.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aloe painting for birthday card</title>
      <link>https://robchoudhury.com/art/aloe-painting/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robchoudhury.com/art/aloe-painting/</guid>
      <description>I have three awesome sisters, so this was the painting I made for my sister Mimi&amp;rsquo;s birthday card. I&amp;rsquo;m lucky that my work is close by to some really cool gardens on campus, including the Ficke Garden just north of the Microbiology Building.
I put this art up on my redbubble account (https://www.redbubble.com/people/robchoudhury) so that I could buy it in sticker format</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sketchnotes of Neil McRoberts&#39; HLB talk</title>
      <link>https://robchoudhury.com/art/mcroberts-hlb/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robchoudhury.com/art/mcroberts-hlb/</guid>
      <description>My former advisor Neil McRoberts gave a seminar at the UF Plant Pathology department about his work on managing the citrus HLB outbreak in California. They have currently found about 1000 trees in the LA basin with HLB, and the program spends about $40m each year, which he has to fight tooth and nail to get. The disease could devestate California&amp;rsquo;s citrus market, so managing it early is critical.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azalea painting for birthday card</title>
      <link>https://robchoudhury.com/art/azalea-painting/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robchoudhury.com/art/azalea-painting/</guid>
      <description>I have three awesome sisters, so this was the painting I made for my sister Abby&amp;rsquo;s birthday card. Florida lights up with tons of azaleas every spring, and my house is surrounded by them, so I wanted her to get a glimpse of some while they were in season. I put this art up on my redbubble account (https://www.redbubble.com/people/robchoudhury) so that I could buy it in sticker format</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Climate Change Book Chapter</title>
      <link>https://robchoudhury.com/art/climate-change-painting/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robchoudhury.com/art/climate-change-painting/</guid>
      <description>I was part of an upcoming book chapter on the threat of climate change for pathogens, and all I could think of was the idea of pathogens on the horizon. I painted a watercolor illustration for the book chapter, maybe it&amp;rsquo;ll be used as the book cover! The painting draws inspiration from Outrun/vaporwave sort of art that became popular in the late 2010&amp;rsquo;s, although the color palette is wayyyy off, it should be neon blue and pink!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amanita Birthday Card Painting</title>
      <link>https://robchoudhury.com/art/amanita-bday-painting/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robchoudhury.com/art/amanita-bday-painting/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m lucky to have some great sisters, so I drew an Amanita and painted it with watercolors and a sharpie pen as a birthday card for her!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>