<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Robin Choudhury on Robin Choudhury</title>
    <link>https://robchoudhury.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Robin Choudhury on Robin Choudhury</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2020 Robin Choudhury</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2017 00:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Spinach Downy Mildew Biofungicide Trials</title>
      <link>https://robchoudhury.com/post/sdm-biofungicides/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robchoudhury.com/post/sdm-biofungicides/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Full analysis is &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/robchoudhury/sdm_biofungicide&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Published in Plant Disease Management Reports &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.plantmanagementnetwork.org/pub/trial/pdmr/volume9/abstracts/v22.asp&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;2014&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.plantmanagementnetwork.org/pub/trial/pdmr/volume10/abstracts/v016.asp&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;2015&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.plantmanagementnetwork.org/pub/trial/pdmr/volume11/abstracts/v017.asp&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;2016&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Throughout my PhD work, it became obvious that the challenges of spinach downy mildew were most heavily impacting organic growers. They were unable to rely on conventional synthetic pesticides that were able to suitably control disease in the conventional crop, and had to rely on resistance to control the disease. I wanted to see if any biofungicide had effect on the disease. I am using the term &amp;lsquo;biofungicide&amp;rsquo; broadly here, meaning any form of pesticide that would be organically based. So this could be things derived from microbes (like Serenade), things derived from naturally occurring chemicals (like Copper), or any organism that would directly impact or prevent disease. We ended up running eight trials over the course of three years, and four of them ended up with disease. Each trial had an untreated control and used a conventional (synthetic) control chemical. I sprayed 2-4 times over the course of 4 weeks, and rated for disease incidence in plots.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-results&#34;&gt;The Results&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://robchoudhury.com/img/img_sdm/fungicidecairo.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we look across all of the chemicals that were used, we see that none of them were able to completely prevent disease, although some were able to significantly reduce disease compared with the untreated control. This suggests that they may be useful in helping to prevent disease in combination with other control options. Trial #2 got a bit out of hand with a late application due to unforseen rain delays, resulting in very high disease ratings, even for the standard chemical control.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;normalizing-the-results&#34;&gt;Normalizing the Results&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But not all of the chemicals were tried in all of the trials. Some became unavailable in later trials, others were introduced to us or growers asked us to trial, and space limitation made it difficult for a few trials. One way to account for this is through meta analysis, although four trials is not nearly enough to do a proper meta-analysis. One alternative is simply to normalize each disease incidence rating to the mean of the untreated control for the trial. This had the result of scaling disease from 0 (complete control compared with untreated control) to infinity (much, much worse than the untreated control), although most of the products fell between 0 and 1. Some of the products (e.g. Actigard, Biospecific, Lifegard, Howler, Zonix) were only included in one trial that ended up with relatively low disease, so they are kind of artifically lower in disease incidence than other products.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://robchoudhury.com/img/img_sdm/fungicidecairo_colored_sorted_scaled.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;conclusions&#34;&gt;Conclusions&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These results suggest there are potential control measures for disease, although they don&amp;rsquo;t seem to completely remove disease risk.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sketchnotes of Ying-Yu Liao&#39;s tomato spot talk</title>
      <link>https://robchoudhury.com/art/liao-tomato/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robchoudhury.com/art/liao-tomato/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ying-Yu Liao gave a nice seminar about her ongoing PhD work looking at Magnesium Oxide nanoparticles and their use for control of bacterial tomato spot disease.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aloe painting for birthday card</title>
      <link>https://robchoudhury.com/art/aloe-painting/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robchoudhury.com/art/aloe-painting/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have three awesome sisters, so this was the painting I made for my sister Mimi&amp;rsquo;s birthday card. I&amp;rsquo;m lucky that my work is close by to some really cool gardens on campus, including the &lt;a href=&#34;https://goo.gl/maps/K8ztnjDdG4VE2oYh9&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Ficke Garden&lt;/a&gt; just north of the Microbiology Building.&lt;br /&gt;
I put this art up on my redbubble account (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.redbubble.com/people/robchoudhury&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://www.redbubble.com/people/robchoudhury&lt;/a&gt;) so that I could buy it in sticker format&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sketchnotes of Neil McRoberts&#39; HLB talk</title>
      <link>https://robchoudhury.com/art/mcroberts-hlb/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robchoudhury.com/art/mcroberts-hlb/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My former advisor &lt;a href=&#34;https://qbelab.plantpathology.ucdavis.edu/neil-mcroberts/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Neil McRoberts&lt;/a&gt; gave a seminar at the UF Plant Pathology department about his work on managing the citrus HLB outbreak in California. They have currently found about 1000 trees in the LA basin with HLB, and the program spends about $40m each year, which he has to fight tooth and nail to get. The disease could devestate California&amp;rsquo;s citrus market, so managing it early is critical.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azalea painting for birthday card</title>
      <link>https://robchoudhury.com/art/azalea-painting/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robchoudhury.com/art/azalea-painting/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have three awesome sisters, so this was the painting I made for my sister Abby&amp;rsquo;s birthday card. Florida lights up with tons of azaleas every spring, and my house is surrounded by them, so I wanted her to get a glimpse of some while they were in season.
I put this art up on my redbubble account (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.redbubble.com/people/robchoudhury&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://www.redbubble.com/people/robchoudhury&lt;/a&gt;) so that I could buy it in sticker format&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Climate Change Book Chapter</title>
      <link>https://robchoudhury.com/art/climate-change-painting/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robchoudhury.com/art/climate-change-painting/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was part of an upcoming book chapter on the threat of climate change for pathogens, and all I could think of was the idea of pathogens on the horizon.
I painted a watercolor illustration for the book chapter, maybe it&amp;rsquo;ll be used as the book cover!
The painting draws inspiration from Outrun/vaporwave sort of art that became popular in the late 2010&amp;rsquo;s, although the color palette is wayyyy off, it should be neon blue and pink!
I put this art up on my redbubble account (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.redbubble.com/people/robchoudhury&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://www.redbubble.com/people/robchoudhury&lt;/a&gt;) so that I could buy it in sticker format&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amanita Birthday Card Painting</title>
      <link>https://robchoudhury.com/art/amanita-bday-painting/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robchoudhury.com/art/amanita-bday-painting/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m lucky to have some great sisters, so I drew an Amanita and painted it with watercolors and a sharpie pen as a birthday card for her!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grape Powdery Mildew Variety Trials</title>
      <link>https://robchoudhury.com/post/gpm-variety/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robchoudhury.com/post/gpm-variety/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Full analysis is &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/robchoudhury/grape_pm_pdmr&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Published in Plant Disease Management Reports &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.plantmanagementnetwork.org/pub/trial/pdmr/volume9/abstracts/smf18.asp&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;2011&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.plantmanagementnetwork.org/pub/trial/pdmr/volume13/abstracts/pf051.asp&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;2012&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During my master&amp;rsquo;s degree, we set out a lot of projects (I had originally intended for my master&amp;rsquo;s to be a PhD&amp;hellip;but thats a story for another time). So I ended up having a ton of different interconnected projects running with Doug Gubler looking at different aspects of grape powdery mildew biology and epidemiology. While we knew that there were differences in how grape varieties and cultivars reacted to powdery mildew, we couldn&amp;rsquo;t find a great resource that looked at the cultivars grown in California in the present. There was a grape vineyard planted in Round Mountain (near Mount Shasta, waaaay up north) that had 10 varieties all grown in a randomized complete block design and were being used by a great grower named Hans Heinrich. Hans was kind and generous enough to let us use his vineyard and equipment to do research, so we sprayed the interior of his vineyard and left the ends of the rows (which contained copies of the varieties) to rate. We rated the vineyard for two years (2011 and 2012) and by the time the second year came up, we knew that I would be transitioning to another lab. We still wanted to get the data together, so we continued to rate the disease and planned on putting together a small manuscript describing our work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We ended up publishing the results of the trials in two separate PDMR documents. Retrospectively, I wish we had published the work in &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.plantmanagementnetwork.org/php/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Plant Health Progress&lt;/a&gt;. The story was really interesting, and we had a ton of data, both in time and across quite a few varieties. I think it would have fit better in that journal than as two separate reports. However, whats done is done, and PHP wasn&amp;rsquo;t quite as prominent then as it is even now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-results&#34;&gt;The Results&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://robchoudhury.com/img/img_ucd/leaf_severity.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
Overall, the results for leaf severity differed slightly between years. In 2011, Merlot had the highest severity, especially towards the end of the season when the severity jumped quite a bit between the final two time points. We rated a little bit later in 2012, and Merlot actually came out near the bottom. Its important to note the scales: Disease severity across the board was waay higher in 2012 for this vineyard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://robchoudhury.com/img/img_ucd/cluster_severity.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
Sauvignon Blanc seemed to be most affected in 2011, although Zinfandel and Pinot Noir were also pretty heavily affected. Pinot Blanc was the most heavily affected cultivar in 2012, so again there is little concordance between the two years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://robchoudhury.com/img/img_ucd/audpc_leaf.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
When comparing across years, its sometimes useful to rely on a more holistic metric, like the area under the disease progress curve (AUDPC). We looked at AUDPC for leaves and found decent concordance between the two years, suggesting that Syrah is less heavily affected than many other cultivars (and is very tasty, to boot!).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://robchoudhury.com/img/img_ucd/leaf_cluster_audpc_concordance.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
When looking at AUDPC ratings for clusters and leaves of different varieties, we can see that some varieties are more heavily affected in the clusters rather than the leaves. This has major implications for assaying for disease susceptibility. We frequently use proxies to measure disease severity: in this case, leaves are more abundant and available (basically) year-round. But using leaves alone to measure disease susceptibility could lead to some over- or under-estimations of how resistant a variety will be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://robchoudhury.com/img/img_ucd/leaf_cluster_concordance.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
When we plot how disease stacked up for leaves and clusters over time, we can see that they don&amp;rsquo;t really concur for the cultivars (a perfect concordance would follow the 1:1 line). Part of this is that leaves are more heavily affected early in the season, as seen in the chart.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;conclusions&#34;&gt;Conclusions&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We found a lot of cool stuff about varieties that are commonly grown in California, but unfortunately the year to year variation in the data made it hard to combine the datasets. I still think that they&amp;rsquo;re rich datasets, and I probably haven&amp;rsquo;t explored them to their fullest.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Haiti Crop Production</title>
      <link>https://robchoudhury.com/post/haiti-production/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robchoudhury.com/post/haiti-production/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/robchoudhury/haiti_production&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Full analysis here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Haiti is one of our nation&amp;rsquo;s nearest neighbors, and has been a key player in world history over the past 200 years. &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Haitian_Revolution&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;The Haitian revolution&lt;/a&gt; took nearly 15 years and cost countless lives, but resulted in one of the first nations that was slave-free and ruled by non-whites and former captives. The loss of Haiti (then called Saint-Domingue) forced the cash-starved Napoleon to sell the Louisiana territory to the United States, one of the single largest land purchases in our countries history. In the ensuing 200 years, Haiti has struggled; as a country founded by former slaves, they were forced to repay reparations for lost &amp;lsquo;property&amp;rsquo; to France (approximately &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/External_debt_of_Haiti&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;$21 Billion&lt;/a&gt;, according to Wikipedia). And &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Haiti%E2%80%93United_States_relations#Donald_Trump%27s_%22shithole_countries%22_comment&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;recent comments&lt;/a&gt; by a world leader suggests that their struggle are far from over. Despite ALL of this, I (personally) knew nearly next to nothing about Haiti prior to a year ago. While I would periodically hear about tragedies like the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/2010_Haiti_earthquake&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;2010 Hatian earthquake&lt;/a&gt; and the subsequent &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/2010_Haiti_earthquake&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;cholera epidemic&lt;/a&gt; (that the UN only recently &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nytimes.com/2016/08/18/world/americas/united-nations-haiti-cholera.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;took responsibility for&lt;/a&gt;), Haiti always remained &amp;hellip; &amp;lsquo;over there&amp;rsquo; in my mind. A place that exists, that I may have learned about, but was never quite close enough for me to think much about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Luckily, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.garrettlab.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Garrett Lab&lt;/a&gt; and University of Florida are involved in a rather large &lt;a href=&#34;https://global.ifas.ufl.edu/area-project/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Feed the Future AREA project&lt;/a&gt; focused on improving Haitian agriculture, and I have learned a lot more in the past year. My labmember &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/joubert-fayette-692a8276/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Dr. Joubert Fayette&lt;/a&gt; is a Haitian national who got his PhD here at the UF Plant Pathology department, and is working to help re-build the diagnostic capabilities of Haiti so that they can detect and respond to threats (you can read more about &lt;a href=&#34;http://blogs.ifas.ufl.edu/ufifasglobal/2017/12/07/54/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;his work with AREA here&lt;/a&gt;). Wanita Dantes and James Fulton are graduate students in garrett lab researching an emerging plantain disease in Haiti that causes the trees to topple over just as they are full of fruit. While my work primarily focuses on laurel wilt disease of avocados in Florida, Haiti and Dominican Republic are some of our nearest neighbors, so we wanted to get an initial look at how at-risk their avocado groves are to Laurel Wilt Disease. We wanted to find some production statistics that might help to explain where production occurs in the country and where we should be monitoring for disease. We were also curious about production statistics for other crops: other projects in Garrett lab focus on a disease that alternatively hosts on mango, and sweetpotato seed trade in Uganda (see more of Kelsey Andersen&amp;rsquo;s work  &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.biorxiv.org/content/biorxiv/early/2017/02/10/107359.full-text.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-data&#34;&gt;The Data&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found a dataset of a report posted by the Haitian Ministry of Agriculture (see it &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.google.com/url?sa=t&amp;amp;rct=j&amp;amp;q=&amp;amp;esrc=s&amp;amp;source=web&amp;amp;cd=1&amp;amp;cad=rja&amp;amp;uact=8&amp;amp;ved=2ahUKEwjAjeLame7fAhXvhOAKHaiNC7YQFjAAegQICRAC&amp;amp;url=http%3A%2F%2Fagriculture.gouv.ht%2Fstatistiques_agricoles%2Fwp-content%2Fuploads%2F2016%2F06%2FRapport-ENPA-2014.pdf&amp;amp;usg=AOvVaw1DO-q2oj2-_3UIshSyoOpk&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; (PDF WARNING)). The report is in French, but I took a few years of french in high school and my grandfather and mother speak french, so I was able to piece together enough. The report describes different levels of production of some important crops in Haiti in different Departments (effectively like states). I got map data of the different Departments from (GADM)[&lt;a href=&#34;https://gadm.org/maps.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://gadm.org/maps.html&lt;/a&gt;], which hosts maps of political boundaries at different levels (country, state, county, town).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;avocado-production&#34;&gt;Avocado Production&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was primarily concerned about finding out more about avocado production in Haiti. Avocado production in Haiti and the Dominican Republic are important both for local and export markets, as well as for food security. Most of the fruit are West Indian types, which are typically greener, and have a less buttery feel to them than Hass varieties. We grow a ton (~8000 acres) of West Indian varieties, and Dominican Republic is our main market competitors. Many of the varieties that are in Haiti were brought there from California and Florida in the mid-1920&amp;rsquo;s to the Central Experiment Station of the Hatian Dept. of Ag. near Port au Prince.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://robchoudhury.com/img/img_agriculture/haiti_avocado_map.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This map shows some fairly heavy production in the Artibonite and Grand-Anse regions as well as in the Nord and Centre Departments. We now need to locate important agricultural ports and run some wind run models to see what is the liklihood of the disease reaching these areas. That is for a future publication&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;banana-and-plantain-production&#34;&gt;Banana and Plantain Production&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were interested in banana and plantain production because of Toppling disease, and it looks (based on this map) like much of the production is in the Ouest Department. We are currently comparing these data to other published data to see if it matches with what has previously been reported for banana production.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://robchoudhury.com/img/img_agriculture/haiti_banana_map.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;mango-production&#34;&gt;Mango Production&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mangos are incredibly delicious (see &lt;a href=&#34;https://robchoudhury.netlify.com/post/miami-mango-ratings/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;my previous blogpost&lt;/a&gt; if you don&amp;rsquo;t believe me!), and are both nutritionally and economically important for Haiti.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://robchoudhury.com/img/img_agriculture/haiti_mango_map.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of Haitian mango production is in the Artibonite and Nord Departments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;sweetpotato-production&#34;&gt;Sweetpotato Production&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sweetpotatoes were the trickiest. The Haitian word, &amp;lsquo;patate&amp;rsquo; sounds VERY close to potato; luckily Joubert corrected my rookie mistake!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://robchoudhury.com/img/img_agriculture/haiti_sweetpotato_map.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like many of the other crops here, there is heavy production in Arbonite Department.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusions&#34;&gt;Conclusions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Haiti is an incredibly resilient country that just needs a little bit of help to make it&amp;rsquo;s agriculture robust and sustainable. I am fortunate to work alongside those involved in the AREA project as they help to rebuild this proud country&amp;rsquo;s capabilities for sustainable agriculture!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Homestead Avocado Ratings</title>
      <link>https://robchoudhury.com/post/avocado-ratings/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robchoudhury.com/post/avocado-ratings/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/robchoudhury/avocado_tasting&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Full analysis here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Global avocado production mostly focuses in Mexico, with the most prominent variety being &amp;lsquo;Hass&amp;rsquo;. I work on a project researching a disease of avocados (and other plants in the same family, Lauraceae) that causes rapid death, laurel wilt. Avocados in Florida are threatened by laurel wilt. Most production occurs in Miami-Dade county, mostly around the Homestead production region. The avocados grown in Florida tend to be of the West Indian races, whereas Hass are Mexican-Guatamalan hybrid races. West Indian races are larger (think about the size of a grapefruit) and are more watery and floral than Hass. Most of the varieties grown in south Florida are not exported because they don&amp;rsquo;t ship well. I was fortunately to go down and gather some avocados from the University of Florida Tropical Research and Extension Center (UF-TREC), where my collaborator &lt;a href=&#34;https://trec.ifas.ufl.edu/faculty/jcrane/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Dr. Jonathan Crane&lt;/a&gt; works. I brought them back north to the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.garrettlab.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Garrett lab in Gainesville&lt;/a&gt;, where we tasted and rated the avocados as they became ripe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here they are!
&lt;img src=&#34;https://robchoudhury.com/img/img_lw/IMG_20181008_084604.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-data&#34;&gt;The Data&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We rated the avocados over the course of about a week, and I have to be honest, by the end I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to see another avocado again for a long time. Eating one avocado is a joy; eating 10 in a very short time span is a slog. In addition, not all of them were very good! Some were better than others, but most of the reviewers thought that the Hass was probably better than most of these. That said, our palates (palletes? I&amp;rsquo;m still thinking about &lt;a href=&#34;https://robchoudhury.netlify.com/post/colors/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;the last blog post&lt;/a&gt;) have been refined to enjoy Hass. If we had grown up with these varieties, we might have had more positive thoughts on them. It took about a week for all of the fruit to ripen, and we ate them as they became ready.  We each did a subjective rating of 1-10, with 1 being &amp;ldquo;this tastes terrible&amp;rdquo;, and 10 being &amp;ldquo;this is literally the best avocado I&amp;rsquo;ve ever had / this is as good as Hass&amp;rdquo;. We rated independent of each other, recording our ratings, and I collated the data for this dataset. Not everyone rated all avocados (except for me), but most people rated at least two.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-did-they-perform&#34;&gt;How Did They Perform?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://robchoudhury.com/img/img_lw/2018-11-20.variety.rating.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So overall, it looks like &lt;em&gt;Lara Red&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Tonnage&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Pahokee&lt;/em&gt; were top of the heap, but the others were all close behind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of the avocados were rich, but not quite as rich as a typical &lt;em&gt;Hass&lt;/em&gt;, which has a nice butteryness and clean mouthfeel. Some of the avocados were watery, which definitely cost them points. Others had distinct off-flavors, kind of vegetative or acrid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;did-people-have-different-views-on-the-avocados&#34;&gt;Did people have different views on the avocados?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://robchoudhury.com/img/img_lw/2018-11-20.variety.rating.person.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;YES! Overall, some people were quite positive about some varieties and negative about others. However, most people had similar ratings across the board, with only a few people with distinct opinions on the avocados. Kelsey and I rated the most avocados over the period, so ours tended to be the most negative. I was curious if there was a relationship between the number of avocados that we rated and the mean avocado rating we had, so I did a simple linear regression of the two.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://robchoudhury.com/img/img_lw/2018-11-20.variety.rating.lm.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was a decent relationship between the two, with an R^2 of 0.4447 and a p value of 0.0297. It seems that for every additional avocado a person rated, their mean rating score dropped by about 0.2, which is noticable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;was-there-an-effect-of-time&#34;&gt;Was there an effect of time?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://robchoudhury.com/img/img_lw/2018-11-20.variety.rating.date.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;YES! It looks like as the week wore on, people got more and more tired of avocados. While the first few varieties garnered wide support, the later varieties were not as popular. However, its difficult to disentangle the effect of rating date with variety itself, as we did not taste the varieties all on the same day, but rather on sequential days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;did-raters-group-together&#34;&gt;Did Raters Group Together?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://robchoudhury.com/img/img_lw/2018-11-20.variety.ordination.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have been looking into community analyses, and I wanted to know whether the ratings performed by each person could help to group the raters into &amp;lsquo;camps&amp;rsquo;. I used the &amp;lsquo;decorana&amp;rsquo; function within the &amp;lsquo;vegan&amp;rsquo; package to conduct a detrended correspondance analysis. I had to fill in the gaps for how people rated, and I filled them in with zeros, which probably screwed up the data and analysis somewhat. It looks like Ricardo and I rated things similarly, and Kelsey and Yanru rated their similarly, but overall there was quite a bit of differentiation among raters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusions&#34;&gt;Conclusions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are in the Miami or Homestead area, try to get your hands on some of the local varieties. They weren&amp;rsquo;t all winners, but it was really interesting to taste the West Indian types and see how they all compare with one another.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Powdery Mildew on Filaree</title>
      <link>https://robchoudhury.com/post/pm-filaree/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robchoudhury.com/post/pm-filaree/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Full data and analysis &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/robchoudhury/pm_filaree&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Publication &lt;a href=&#34;https://apsjournals.apsnet.org/doi/full/10.1094/PDIS-05-15-0527-PDN&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;powdery-mildew-on-whitestem-filaree&#34;&gt;Powdery Mildew on Whitestem Filaree&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was walking around my neighborhood in Davis, CA one day when I noticed a strange looking weed on the ground that had powdery mildew on it&amp;rsquo;s surface. Powdery mildews are a group of biotrophic fungi that I had studied for my master&amp;rsquo;s degree. They are often times host specific, and do not regularly kill their host, but rather sap nutrients and water from the epidermal cells. Because powdery mildews are so host specific, and because diseases of weeds are often underreported, I was interested in seeing whether this was a new interaction for California.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After running home and grabbing some nitrile gloves and ziplock bags, I collected some samples and headed off for work. I had a close working relationship with Dr. Doug Gubler&amp;rsquo;s lab because I did my master&amp;rsquo;s degree there, so I was able to use their compound microscope to look at the conidia at a higher magnification.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://robchoudhury.com/img/img_ucd/SNAP-113923-0006.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;conidial-measurements&#34;&gt;Conidial Measurements&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The conidia of the powdery mildew had some distinct fibrosin bodies (the shiny bits inside the cells) which are kind of diagnostic for species of &lt;em&gt;Podosphaera&lt;/em&gt;. The conidia looked like they were forming in chains, and the shape of the appressoria (how the fungus accesses plant nutrients in the epidermis) looked nipple-shaped. All of these morphological lines of evidence suggested that the fungus was in the genus &lt;em&gt;Podosphaera&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We wanted to take measurements of different microscopic portions of the fungus to compare with those of described species, so we measured the length of the conidiophore as well as the length and width of the conidia themselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://robchoudhury.com/img/img_ucd/conidiophore_length_filaree_pm.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The conidiophore lengths were typical for &lt;em&gt;Podosphaera&lt;/em&gt; spp., and the length to width ratio were as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://robchoudhury.com/img/img_ucd/length_width_ratio_filaree_pm.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;phylogenetic-analysis&#34;&gt;Phylogenetic Analysis&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We wanted to know how our isolate was phylogenetically related to other isolates within the genus &lt;em&gt;Podosphaera&lt;/em&gt;. This might help us narrow down which species the isolate belongs to, as well as provides the scientific community more broadly a record for the isolate that we had collected. We isolated DNA and amplified for parts of the internal transcribed spacer (ITS) region, a highly variable region flanked by stable sequences, allowing for relatively high-resolution phylogenetic identification of isolates of fungi. We compared our isolates to those of other &lt;em&gt;Podosphaera&lt;/em&gt; species, and found that our isolate was identical to a sequence for a supposed &lt;em&gt;Podosphaera xanthii&lt;/em&gt; that was collected from papaya in asia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://robchoudhury.com/img/img_ucd/podosphaera_filaree_phylogeny.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-case-of-mistaken-identity&#34;&gt;A Case of Mistaken Identity?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, when we compare the &lt;em&gt;P. xanthii&lt;/em&gt; that most closely matched with our &lt;em&gt;Podosphaera&lt;/em&gt; isolate, we found that the isolate was not monophyletically grouped with other &lt;em&gt;P. xanthii&lt;/em&gt; isolates. This could have occurred if the original identification was incorrect or if the samples or sequences got mixed up while in submission. Both of these things happen more often than I think most scientists would care to admit. Comparing the morphology of our isolate with others in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://my.apsnet.org/ItemDetail?iProductCode=51892&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Taxonomic Manual of the Erysiphales (Powdery Mildews)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, we found that our isolate most closely resembled &lt;em&gt;Podosphaera erodii&lt;/em&gt;, which had been reported in Europe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because powdery mildew isolates are biotrophic, the only way to conclusively define our isolate as &lt;em&gt;Podosphaera erodii&lt;/em&gt; would be to go to the collections in Europe and examine them. That was far out of the budget that the project had (a whopping $0), so without a complementary confirming sequence, we had to define our species as &lt;em&gt;Podosphaera&lt;/em&gt; cf. &lt;em&gt;erodii&lt;/em&gt;, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cf.&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&amp;lsquo;cf.&amp;rsquo;&lt;/a&gt; referring to contrasting our isolate with a known isolate where there is uncertainty in taxonomy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusions&#34;&gt;Conclusions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Describing the diversity of life is critical to understanding what we face to lose in the case of extreme habitat loss and climate change. Oftentimes, the death of a single species is not a single death, but rather a cascading event that affects all of the species that rely on that extinct group. Pathogens and parasites are thought to be some of the the largest groups of life, with each species having multiple host-specific pathogens and parasites. As we lose diversity, these groups that may have been useful for biocontrol of weeds or for pharmological purposes are lost as well, and we need to consider how this may have cascading effects throughout the landscape.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Colors</title>
      <link>https://robchoudhury.com/post/colors/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robchoudhury.com/post/colors/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;There has been more and more research on how to better design figures and color schemes to suit a broader audience. Roughly 8% of men and 0.5% of women have some sort of colorblindness, so if I present a figure during an extension or scientific talk, I really need to make sure that the information comes across correctly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Luckily, there are lots of great packages out there that give options on what color scales I can use. I really wanted to keep track of some of my favorites, and how I created the visualizations, so this is kind of a short guide on that. There are lots of other resources out there, this is something that I kept going back to as a reference, and wanted to make public.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-color-scales-are-available&#34;&gt;What Color Scales are Available?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are many MANY packages that make color palettes, ( &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/EmilHvitfeldt/paletteer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;paletteer&lt;/a&gt; seems to be an R resource for many of them), but the classic that my colleagues and I use alot is &lt;a href=&#34;https://cran.r-project.org/web/packages/viridis/vignettes/intro-to-viridis.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;viridis&lt;/a&gt;, which offers five beautiful palettes. I wanted to compare those five to some others that I found around and thought looked interesting and kind of similar to the viridis five.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;pals::pal.bands(pals::ocean.thermal, viridis::plasma, viridis::magma,pals::ocean.matter, pals::ocean.oxy, viridis::inferno, viridis::viridis, pals::parula , pals::ocean.haline, viridis::cividis)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://robchoudhury.com/img/img_colors/colors_compare.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So the palettes that are available through the pals package seem to be useful, and seem to mimic what we see in viridis. I really like the Parula palette, it reminds me of the old-school Matlab plots, very retro chic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-colorblind-friendly-are-any-of-these-palettes&#34;&gt;How Colorblind-Friendly are Any of these Palettes?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As much as it&amp;rsquo;s interesting to see the different palettes, we really want to know how they will be perceived by those with different forms of colorblindness. Ideally, we would want a color palette that looks like it ramps fairly smoothly over the entire range, and that the ramp looks uniformly smooth across the different colorblindness types.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;pals::pal.safe(pals::parula)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://robchoudhury.com/img/img_colors/colors_cb_safe.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It looks like the Parula palette is fairly safe and uniform for those with BW/Deutan/Protan blindness, but not as uniform for Tritan. Ideally, we would want a palette that can cover all of them. Check out this great article describing the creation of the cividis color palette &lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/abs/1712.01662&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, and how it is likely one of the more optimal settings for figures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-are-the-actual-colors&#34;&gt;What are the Actual Colors?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes you want to use the hex codes involved in the different palettes. I use the scales function show_col to show the different colors, and here I am using the rcartocolor package palette &amp;lsquo;ag_Sunset&amp;rsquo;, which I find incredibly beautiful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;scales::show_col(colorRampPalette(rcartocolor::carto_pal(name = &amp;ldquo;ag_Sunset&amp;rdquo;))(25))&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://robchoudhury.com/img/img_colors/ag_sunset.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusions&#34;&gt;Conclusions?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is really and truly just the tip of the iceberg, but with a small amount of care, you can easily modify your scientific figures to be more easily and accurately understood by a fairly large chunk of the populace.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cyclosporiapsis Outbreak in Texas 2017</title>
      <link>https://robchoudhury.com/post/cyclosporiapsis-outbreak-in-texas-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robchoudhury.com/post/cyclosporiapsis-outbreak-in-texas-2017/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/robchoudhury/TexasCyclospora&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;You can find the code for this post at&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cyclosporiasis is an intestinal sickness caused by the coccidian parasite &lt;em&gt;Cyclospora cayetanensis&lt;/em&gt;. An outbreak in 2017 seemingly from Mexican cilantro has affected many people, and the Texas public health board and CDC put out some of the data publically. I wanted to go through this data, make choropleth plots for the counties affected (because I am unfamiliar with Texan counties) and plot out the data. This was also prompted because I ate some cilantro and immediately went into hypochondriac mode.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;where-is-the-outbreak-occurring-in-texas&#34;&gt;Where is the Outbreak Occurring in Texas?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://robchoudhury.com/img/img_cyclospora/Aug02.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://robchoudhury.com/img/img_cyclospora/Aug22.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over a 20-day period, the several counties in Texas. Things really light up in the counties that countain big cities like Houston, Austin, and Dallas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-happened-over-the-course-of-the-epidemic&#34;&gt;What Happened Over the Course of the Epidemic?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://robchoudhury.com/img/img_cyclospora/timeline.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://robchoudhury.com/img/img_cyclospora/totalcases.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Based on the CDC dataset, we can see that things get pretty bad, but start to settle down after mid-July. This may have been due to raised awareness of the outbreak or removal of the affected material from shelves and stores.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusions&#34;&gt;Conclusions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, this outbreak highlighted the interconnectedness of agricultural trade, especially with Mexico, and the vulnerability of these systems to even small amounts of distant contamination. Understanding epidemic dynamics and mapping out locations of disease can help to highlight areas that are especially susceptible to problems.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summary measures of predictive power associated with logistic regression models of disease risk</title>
      <link>https://robchoudhury.com/publication/gareth_sdm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robchoudhury.com/publication/gareth_sdm/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Miami Mango Ratings</title>
      <link>https://robchoudhury.com/post/miami-mango-ratings/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robchoudhury.com/post/miami-mango-ratings/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/robchoudhury/mango_rating&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Full analysis here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mangos are grown widely in South Florida, but only a few varieties ever make it north, because they don’t really ship well and there isn’t a huge market. I ended up receiving some rare varieties from a collaborator down south, and I wanted to know how they ranked one to another, so my wife and I rated the different varieties.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-data&#34;&gt;The Data&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My wife and I rated the mangoes over the course of about a week, tasting the different varieties as they felt more and more ripe. We each did a subjective rating of 1-10, with 1 being &amp;ldquo;this tastes terrible&amp;rdquo;, and 10 being &amp;ldquo;this is literally the best mango I&amp;rsquo;ve ever had&amp;rdquo;. We rated independent of each other, recording our ratings, and I collated the data for this dataset.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-did-they-perform&#34;&gt;How Did They Perform?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://robchoudhury.com/img/img_mango/variety_rating.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So overall, it looks like &lt;em&gt;Kensington Pride&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Hayden&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Edwards&lt;/em&gt; were clear winners, and the other varieties were not. What happened?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you look at the other data in the file (filled with NA&amp;rsquo;s, sorry) there are notes on the stringiness and the taste of the varieties. Poor varieties like &lt;em&gt;Sweet Tart&lt;/em&gt; had chalky texture in the mouth, and would sometimes smell like tylenol, or have no aroma at all. Good performers had very slight to no stringiness, and had the kind of &amp;lsquo;quintessential&amp;rsquo; tastes of mango: fruity, tropical, rich. &lt;em&gt;Kensington Pride&lt;/em&gt; was my favorite, and it tasted a bit like muscadine grapes. Mid-performers like &lt;em&gt;Nam Duk Moi&lt;/em&gt; had stringiness, and &lt;em&gt;Dot&lt;/em&gt; would sometimes have a popcorn like flavor, or tasted too sweet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Did my wife and I have different views on these mangos?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://robchoudhury.com/img/img_mango/person_rating_dumbbell.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had fairly similar ratings, but it looks like I pretty consistently rated things more favorably than she did.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusions&#34;&gt;Conclusions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are in Miami area in July, you NEED to taste mangoes. They grow on street trees, make friends, knock on doors, see if people will sell them to you. Have fun!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
