<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Robin Choudhury on Robin Choudhury</title>
    <link>https://robchoudhury.netlify.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Robin Choudhury on Robin Choudhury</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018 Robin Choudhury</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2017 00:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Cyclosporiapsis Outbreak in Texas 2017</title>
      <link>https://robchoudhury.netlify.com/post/cyclosporiapsis-outbreak-in-texas-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robchoudhury.netlify.com/post/cyclosporiapsis-outbreak-in-texas-2017/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/robchoudhury/TexasCyclospora&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;You can find the code for this post at&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cyclosporiasis is an intestinal sickness caused by the coccidian parasite &lt;em&gt;Cyclospora cayetanensis&lt;/em&gt;. An outbreak in 2017 seemingly from Mexican cilantro has affected many people, and the Texas public health board and CDC put out some of the data publically. I wanted to go through this data, make choropleth plots for the counties affected (because I am unfamiliar with Texan counties) and plot out the data. This was also prompted because I ate some cilantro and immediately went into hypochondriac mode.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;where-is-the-outbreak-occurring-in-texas&#34;&gt;Where is the Outbreak Occurring in Texas?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://robchoudhury.netlify.com/img/img_cyclospora/Aug02.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://robchoudhury.netlify.com/img/img_cyclospora/Aug22.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over a 20-day period, the several counties in Texas. Things really light up in the counties that countain big cities like Houston, Austin, and Dallas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-happened-over-the-course-of-the-epidemic&#34;&gt;What Happened Over the Course of the Epidemic?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://robchoudhury.netlify.com/img/img_cyclospora/timeline.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://robchoudhury.netlify.com/img/img_cyclospora/totalcases.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Based on the CDC dataset, we can see that things get pretty bad, but start to settle down after mid-July. This may have been due to raised awareness of the outbreak or removal of the affected material from shelves and stores.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusions&#34;&gt;Conclusions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, this outbreak highlighted the interconnectedness of agricultural trade, especially with Mexico, and the vulnerability of these systems to even small amounts of distant contamination. Understanding epidemic dynamics and mapping out locations of disease can help to highlight areas that are especially susceptible to problems.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Miami Mango Ratings</title>
      <link>https://robchoudhury.netlify.com/post/miami-mango-ratings/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robchoudhury.netlify.com/post/miami-mango-ratings/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/robchoudhury/mango_rating&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Full analysis here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mangos are grown widely in South Florida, but only a few varieties ever make it north, because they don’t really ship well and there isn’t a huge market. I ended up receiving some rare varieties from a collaborator down south, and I wanted to know how they ranked one to another, so my wife and I rated the different varieties.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-data&#34;&gt;The Data&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My wife and I rated the mangoes over the course of about a week, tasting the different varieties as they felt more and more ripe. We each did a subjective rating of 1-10, with 1 being &amp;ldquo;this tastes terrible&amp;rdquo;, and 10 being &amp;ldquo;this is literally the best mango I&amp;rsquo;ve ever had&amp;rdquo;. We rated independent of each other, recording our ratings, and I collated the data for this dataset.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-did-they-perform&#34;&gt;How Did They Perform?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://robchoudhury.netlify.com/img/img_mango/variety_rating.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So overall, it looks like &lt;em&gt;Kensington Pride&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Hayden&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Edwards&lt;/em&gt; were clear winners, and the other varieties were not. What happened?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you look at the other data in the file (filled with NA&amp;rsquo;s, sorry) there are notes on the stringiness and the taste of the varieties. Poor varieties like &lt;em&gt;Sweet Tart&lt;/em&gt; had chalky texture in the mouth, and would sometimes smell like tylenol, or have no aroma at all. Good performers had very slight to no stringiness, and had the kind of &amp;lsquo;quintessential&amp;rsquo; tastes of mango: fruity, tropical, rich. &lt;em&gt;Kensington Pride&lt;/em&gt; was my favorite, and it tasted a bit like muscadine grapes. Mid-performers like &lt;em&gt;Nam Duk Moi&lt;/em&gt; had stringiness, and &lt;em&gt;Dot&lt;/em&gt; would sometimes have a popcorn like flavor, or tasted too sweet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Did my wife and I have different views on these mangos?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://robchoudhury.netlify.com/img/img_mango/person_rating_dumbbell.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had fairly similar ratings, but it looks like I pretty consistently rated things more favorably than she did.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusions&#34;&gt;Conclusions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are in Miami area in July, you NEED to taste mangoes. They grow on street trees, make friends, knock on doors, see if people will sell them to you. Have fun!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bird Ages</title>
      <link>https://robchoudhury.netlify.com/post/bird-ages/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robchoudhury.netlify.com/post/bird-ages/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;bird-age&#34;&gt;Bird Age&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Full analysis &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/robchoudhury/birdage&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I stumbled across a dataset of bird ages on a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.pwrc.usgs.gov/bbl/longevity/longevity_main.cfm&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;USGS website&lt;/a&gt;, and wanted to know if there was a relationship between bird age and other variables (weight, wingspan, etc).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;link-between-bird-age-and-phylogenetic-order&#34;&gt;Link Between Bird Age and Phylogenetic Order?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wanted to know if there was any signal for how old birds get if theyre closely related. Ultimately, I would love to know how age is affected by size (weight, wingspan, whatever) but I cant find open datasets for that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://robchoudhury.netlify.com/img/img_bird_age/joy_plot.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looks like some bird orders have individuals that live longer than others, but it&amp;rsquo;s difficult to say for some whether thats just a sampling issue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;mean-variance-relationship&#34;&gt;Mean Variance Relationship&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The relationship between the mean and the variance of a dataset can tell you &amp;hellip; stuff (see &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Variance_function&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Variance_function&lt;/a&gt;). Honestly I was just curious if there was a relationship, I need to revisit why this bit is important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://robchoudhury.netlify.com/img/img_bird_age/mean_variance.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It looks like there is a pretty strong relationship between log mean and log variance, with an R&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; of 0.3722, a slope of 0.14848.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;next-up&#34;&gt;Next Up?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ideally, it would be awesome to find a dataset that tied bird name with bird weight or wingspan or other variables. That way you could see if bird weight/wingspan correlated with age or phylogeny. It would also be cool to see a tree of bird orders to see if more closely related things had similar ages.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Climate change, carbon dioxide, and pest biology, managing the future: coffee as a case study</title>
      <link>https://robchoudhury.netlify.com/publication/climate_change_coffee/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robchoudhury.netlify.com/publication/climate_change_coffee/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Network analysis: a systems framework to address grand challenges in plant pathology</title>
      <link>https://robchoudhury.netlify.com/publication/network_annualreview/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robchoudhury.netlify.com/publication/network_annualreview/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Privacy Policy</title>
      <link>https://robchoudhury.netlify.com/privacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jun 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robchoudhury.netlify.com/privacy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multiple origins of downy mildews and mitonuclear  discordance within the paraphyletic genus Phytophthora</title>
      <link>https://robchoudhury.netlify.com/publication/dm_phylogeny/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robchoudhury.netlify.com/publication/dm_phylogeny/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A framework for optimizing phytosanitary thresholds in seed systems</title>
      <link>https://robchoudhury.netlify.com/publication/phytosanitarythresholds/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robchoudhury.netlify.com/publication/phytosanitarythresholds/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Temperature and light effects on germination of Peronospora effusa sporangia</title>
      <link>https://robchoudhury.netlify.com/publication/sdm_germination/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robchoudhury.netlify.com/publication/sdm_germination/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Laurel wilt in natural and agricultural ecosystems: understanding the drivers and scales of complex pathosystems</title>
      <link>https://robchoudhury.netlify.com/publication/laurel_wilt_review/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robchoudhury.netlify.com/publication/laurel_wilt_review/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First report of powdery mildew caused by Podosphaera sp. on Triadica sebifera in California</title>
      <link>https://robchoudhury.netlify.com/publication/powdery_mildew_tallowtree/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robchoudhury.netlify.com/publication/powdery_mildew_tallowtree/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spatiotemporal patterns in the airborne dispersal of spinach downy mildew</title>
      <link>https://robchoudhury.netlify.com/publication/spatiotemporal_sdm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robchoudhury.netlify.com/publication/spatiotemporal_sdm/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Season-long dynamics of spinach downy mildew determined by spore trapping and disease incidence</title>
      <link>https://robchoudhury.netlify.com/publication/season_long_sdm/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robchoudhury.netlify.com/publication/season_long_sdm/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First report of powdery mildew of Erodium moschatum caused by Podosphaera cf. erodii in California</title>
      <link>https://robchoudhury.netlify.com/publication/powdery_mildew_erodium/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robchoudhury.netlify.com/publication/powdery_mildew_erodium/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First report of Cytospora punicae causing wood canker and branch dieback of pomegranate (Punica granatum) in the United States</title>
      <link>https://robchoudhury.netlify.com/publication/franci_cytospora/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robchoudhury.netlify.com/publication/franci_cytospora/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
